<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ebroerse.nl/nl/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://ebroerse.nl/nl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><updated>2024-03-20T13:13:20+00:00</updated><id>https://ebroerse.nl/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><entry xml:lang="en-us"><title type="html">Home Automation</title><link href="https://ebroerse.nl/nl/blog/2023/home-automation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Home Automation"/><published>2023-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2023/home-automation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2023/home-automation/"><![CDATA[<p>A collection of software and APIs to control Zappi, NIBE heat pump and SolarEdge PV.</p> <ul> <li> <p>Myenergi (Zappi) API: <a href="https://myenergi.info/api-acronyms-t3154.html">https://myenergi.info/api-acronyms-t3154.html</a></p> </li> <li> <p>Zappi Forum on API: <a href="https://myenergi.info/extracting-energy-data-t7445-s90.html">https://myenergi.info/extracting-energy-data-t7445-s90.html</a></p> </li> <li> <p>pymyenergy Python3 code:</p> <p><a href="https://github.com/twonk/MyEnergi-App-Api">https://github.com/twonk/MyEnergi-App-Api</a></p> <p><a href="https://github.com/ashleypittman/mec">https://github.com/ashleypittman/mec</a></p> </li> <li> <p>Home Assistant: <a href="https://www.home-assistant.io/installation/macos">https://www.home-assistant.io/installation/macos</a></p> </li> <li> <p>NIBE API: <a href="https://github.com/elupus/hass_nibe">https://github.com/elupus/hass_nibe</a></p> </li> <li> <p>Current Sensing with Raspberry Pi: <a href="https://www.instructables.com/Current-Monitoring-With-Raspberry-Pi/">https://www.instructables.com/Current-Monitoring-With-Raspberry-Pi/</a></p> </li> <li> <p>Oracle VirtualBox (to install Home Assistant OS:): <a href="https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/End-user_documentation">https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/End-user_documentation</a></p> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="smart home"/><category term="myenergi"/><category term="zappi"/><category term="NIBE"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A collection of software and APIs to control Zappi, NIBE heat pump and SolarEdge PV.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="nl"><title type="html">Kalkverf</title><link href="https://ebroerse.nl/nl/blog/2023/kalkverf/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kalkverf"/><published>2023-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2023/kalkverf</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2023/kalkverf/"><![CDATA[<p>Vandaag de wanden in de hal in de <a href="https://serefni.is/vara/primer-nf21-kalkgrunnur/">NF21 Uniwall Primer</a> gezet, als voorbereiding voor een laag Stoopen &amp; Meeus <a href="http://www.stoopen-meeus.com/minerale-afwerkingen/kalk/">Kalkverf</a>.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blog/C8CA39CF-DB28-45DB-A2E2-56C1083CFFDA.jpeg" alt=""/></p> <p>Elke keer weer een bijzonder effect als je alle oude kleuren en reparaties wegwerkt onder een effen, lichtgrijze kleur: opeens zijn het geen wanden/bouwwerk meer maar een ruimte.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blog/B914367A-9EEF-4BB1-981F-2C111CA163D2-scaled.jpeg" alt=""/></p> <p>Volgende dagen 2 lagen naturel Kalkverf er overheen vanaf de rolsteiger, geleend van een buurman. Buiten regent het toch!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="art-kunst"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vandaag de wanden in de hal in de NF21 Uniwall Primer gezet, als voorbereiding voor een laag Stoopen &amp; Meeus Kalkverf.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en-us"><title type="html">Busytown under Corona</title><link href="https://ebroerse.nl/nl/blog/2020/busytown-under-corona/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Busytown under Corona"/><published>2020-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2020/busytown-under-corona</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2020/busytown-under-corona/"><![CDATA[<p>Read the whole <strong><a href="https://issues.org/a-world-made-by-belief-scarry-pandemic/#.Xq2mSeQgdB8.link">Busytown</a></strong> series by <a href="https://issues.org/byline/clark-a-miller">Clark A.</a> Miller in <a href="https://issues.org/a-world-made-by-belief-scarry-pandemic/#.Xq2mSeQgdB8.link">Issues</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="science-wetenschap"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read the whole Busytown series by Clark A. Miller in Issues.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="nl"><title type="html">HDL LocoBooster installation issue fixed</title><link href="https://ebroerse.nl/nl/blog/2018/hdl-locobuffer-installation-issue-fixed/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HDL LocoBooster installation issue fixed"/><published>2018-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2018/hdl-locobuffer-installation-issue-fixed</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2018/hdl-locobuffer-installation-issue-fixed/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="ervaring--oplossing">Ervaring &amp; Oplossing</h1> <p>Ik heb de <a href="https://locohdl.synology.me">HDL LocoBooster</a> 3.8 gebouwd en aangesloten op mijn LocoNet.</p> <h2 id="probleem">Probleem:</h2> <p>Mijn Command Station is een klassieke Digitrax Zephyr DCS50. Aan de 1e LocoNet aansluiting op de Zephyr zit alleen de LocoBooster (en aan de LocoBooster uitgang zitten de rails). Aan de 2e LocoNet uitgang van de Zephyr hangen mijn decoders en op RailA/Rail B zitten Digitrax DS54/64 wisseldecoders.</p> <p>(4x gecheckt dat er nog ergens een aansluiting van de rails ook op de Zephyr Rail A/B aansluiting zit. Is een bestaande baan. Toch nog ergens verstopt 1 Rail A aansluiting naar de verkeerde bus.)</p> <ul> <li>Als ik de LocoNet kabel én de rails op de LocoBuffer aansluit, en op de Zephyr de baanspanning inschakel, gaan alle ledjes op de LocoBuffer zachter branden en er klinkt een zoemtoon uit de board.</li> <li>Als ik de Ground-draden uit de LocoNet kabel tussen de LocoBooster en Zephyr doorknip, dan is het weg maar schakelt het relais niet betrouwbaar volgens de Power-knop op de Zephyr. Moet in elk geval 1 x uit en 1 x aan.</li> <li>Een andere voeding maakt geen verschil.</li> </ul> <p>Ik heb geen zware verbindingsdraad aangesloten tussen de Zephyr Ground (Common) aansluiting en de LocoBooster Ground.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blog/Zephyr-Rear-Panel-150x55.png" alt=""/></p> <p>Lees wel hierover (“same reference level”) maar Hans Deloof vermeldt het niet. Dit bleek ook niet nodig.</p> <p>Als ik de rails-aansluiting losschroef van de LocoBuffer en - alleen - de ground terminal even aantik zie ik een vonk (en de LEDs gaan ook zachter branden + een 1 Hz zoemtoon met vage locatie).</p> <p>Ik mat tussen de booster uitgang en de Zephyr Rail A een hoge weerstand van 15kOhm, maar niet 0. Dus: dat is de interne weerstand van de Zephyr</p> <h2 id="double-check-your-wiring">Double check your wiring!</h2> <p>Wat bleek: ik had ergens halverwege de baan de Zephyr Rail A busdraad op de Booster/Track A busdraad aangesloten (en omgekeerd). Dus de rail werd nu gevoed door beide boosters = problemen!</p> <p>Toen dat hersteld was, deed de Booster het met een gewone LocoNet kabel prima. Totdat ik op de vrije uitgangen een schakelaar monteerde (en er op drukte)… Adres kwijt etc.</p> <p>De LocoBooster heeft een verbinding tussen de LocoNet zijde en 1 pool van de booster externe voeding. Ik heb na een tijdje een andere booster met een zgn. H-bridge gemonteerd. Die heeft wel een scheiding naar LocoNet dus eindelijk weer rijden.</p> <p>Pas een jaar later ontdekte ik na het verplaatsen van een Digitrax BD1 bezetmelder, dat die ook stroom laat lopen van de rails naar LocoNet (via de terugmelddecoder waar je de zwarte/rode sensordraadjes op aansluit). Toen ik de korte <a href="https://www.digitrax.com/media/apps/products/detection-signaling/bd1/documents/BD1%20Inst.pdf">handleiding</a> las snapte ik al niet hoe de BD1 bij bezetmelding de ingang naar +5V trekt als hij alleen met de massa van de SE8c is verbonden. De BD1 (en BD4 vermoed ik) is dus alleen te gebruiken in een 100% Digitrax systeem, met die “aarde”-draad tussen alle onderdelen.</p> <p>Een derde kans misschien voor de LocoBooster waar dit stukje mee begon…</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="trains-treinen"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ervaring &amp; Oplossing]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en-us"><title type="html">Leibniz 01</title><link href="https://ebroerse.nl/nl/blog/2018/leibniz-01/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leibniz 01"/><published>2018-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2018/leibniz-01</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2018/leibniz-01/"><![CDATA[<p>Walking the <a href="http://www.herrenhaeuser-gaerten.de">Herrenhausen Garten</a> in Hannover we saw large 1’s and 0’s on a pavilion near the baroque gardens. Intrigued by these “modern” patterns as a Java developer, I learned they were painted in 2016 to honour <a href="http://leibniz-binary.com">Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz</a>, the inventor of the binary system 300 years ago.</p> <p><img src="/img/blog/Leibniz-E-01000101-300x212.jpg" alt="Postcard"/></p> <p><a href="http://leibniz-binary.com/binaercode-alphabet">Leibniz site</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="computers"/><category term="science-wetenschap"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Walking the Herrenhausen Garten in Hannover we saw large 1’s and 0’s on a pavilion near the baroque gardens. Intrigued by these “modern” patterns as a Java developer, I learned they were painted in 2016 to honour Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz, the inventor of the binary system 300 years ago.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en-us"><title type="html">LocoIO update</title><link href="https://ebroerse.nl/nl/blog/2018/locoio-update/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LocoIO update"/><published>2018-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2018/locoio-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2018/locoio-update/"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve built another HDL LocoIO board. Hope to configure it using JMRI 4.12.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blog/img_6667.jpg" alt="LocoIO board assembled 4/2018" title="LocoIO"/></p> <p>Not yet in JMRI 4.11.6. I’m working to get the tool operating with the newer hardware.</p> <p>Update: JMRI 4.15.5 contains more options to configure these boards, as well as HDL LocoBooster and LocoServo boards (ports 1-5 to start with).</p> <p>Please report your results!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="trains-treinen"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve built another HDL LocoIO board. Hope to configure it using JMRI 4.12.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en-us"><title type="html">Translation Dilemmas</title><link href="https://ebroerse.nl/nl/blog/2018/translation-dilemmas/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Translation Dilemmas"/><published>2018-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2018/translation-dilemmas</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2018/translation-dilemmas/"><![CDATA[<p>I’m glad to see users actively discussing how JMRI could perhaps better support their way of using it on their layout. As one of the people persons working on JMRI Localization in the last years, may I add a couple of points to this thread in order to prevent some disappointment and share the dilemmas involved?Exchanging ideas in our community can help improve JMRI. We will certainly hold different opinions on this subject. Let’s promise not to destroy other people’s efforts and take note of the policies regarding language that the likes of Apple and Microsoft adhere to. </p> <p>We are talking about a couple of different dictionaries. To clarify, let’s distinguish:</p> <ol> <li> <p>The language used in the JMRI interface (menus, dialog text etc).</p> </li> <li> <p>The Locale being modelled (or is that spelled ‘modeled’?): terms like Turnout positions Thrown-Closed, Signal Aspects etc.</p> </li> <li> <p>The language used for JMRI Help screens that pop up when you choose the Help &gt; Window Help menu, or view in a web browser as the jmri.org help pages.</p> </li> </ol> <p>Let’s study an example:</p> <p>You are a French-speaking Canadian modelling a Dutch layout.</p> <p>Your computer is set to display menus in French, Imprimer for Print etc. So is JMRI, the Turnout Table is called Aiguillages (in the Tableaux menu).</p> <p>As for the prototype, you would want the signal to display “Stoppen voor het sein” as an Aspect name, not “Arrêter” or the US “Stop”. As long as no French translation is added to the JMRI Prorail signal definitions, that works fine, but as soon as one would be added, it will show up and the only way to prevent would be to switch all of JMRI to Dutch. Not very practical, as modelling a couple of bright yellow trains then requires you to learn a complete language in order to find the Print menu.</p> <p>Still, as a French speaker you’re lucky to have JMRI Help screens available in French. But they won’t mention the country you model, just the French names for the menu options.</p> <p><strong>Notes</strong></p> <p>Ad 1: To me it seems most elegant to set that identical to the rest of the computer it’s running on. So Print… is called Print… (or ‘Druk af…’ in Dutch). If somebody (you?) took the time to provide translations, any user can activate this as described. Try Japanese (but take care and use a new profile, as even the Language choices will display in Japanese!)</p> <p>Ad 2: One could argue that something like the Entry-Exit (NX) Warrant is part of a British English locale, just like a Dispatcher is typical of US railroading and may or may not be translated to eg. a British or European replacement.</p> <p>Ad 3: This is stored in some 2.800 files (80 MB for each language). It would seem fantastic to view this help in your chosen language, but that is a lot of work. and was only done for English (the default) and French. Keeping these two in sync is pretty hard!</p> <ul> <li> <p>There is only one setting to choose from inside JMRI in JMRI Preferences &gt; Display. In Java this applies one of - ISO standardised - 2-letter language abbreviations, eg. _en./_fr. to have all Swing (interface) strings that are written to support Internationalization (I18N in short) to use the _mylanguage.properties file - is it exists.</p> </li> <li> <p>If a properties file with your abbreviation isn’t found, Java/JMRI wil use the default set, which we agreed on to display US English text.</p> </li> <li> <p>Currently, the same trick won’t work for the JMRI Help pages. The whole set has to be copied, including all images as they also will include menus etc. in some language.</p> </li> <li> <p>You can “localize” much of your own Operations stuff like places and train names, but words like Conductor and Return-When-Empty will follow your Locale setting (if available).</p> </li> </ul> <p>All I hope to have demonstrated is that there is no simple trick to make everyone happy, and there’s often an unexpected down side.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="trains-treinen"/><category term="jmri"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m glad to see users actively discussing how JMRI could perhaps better support their way of using it on their layout. As one of the people persons working on JMRI Localization in the last years, may I add a couple of points to this thread in order to prevent some disappointment and share the dilemmas involved?Exchanging ideas in our community can help improve JMRI. We will certainly hold different opinions on this subject. Let’s promise not to destroy other people’s efforts and take note of the policies regarding language that the likes of Apple and Microsoft adhere to. ]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en-us"><title type="html">Assembling the RLW Nn3 K-27 kit</title><link href="https://ebroerse.nl/nl/blog/2017/assembling-the-rlw-nn3-k-27-kit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Assembling the RLW Nn3 K-27 kit"/><published>2017-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2017/assembling-the-rlw-nn3-k-27-kit</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2017/assembling-the-rlw-nn3-k-27-kit/"><![CDATA[<p>I had this RLW kit waiting for a couple of years. Finally, the time came to build it.</p> <p>As the pictures in my kit instructions were not very clearly printed, I wrote this addendum to provide some extra information to fellow model builders. As long as you study the instruction sheet in well advance, regularly compare it to your parts and work in small steps, wear extra visors if needed, this can be a great kit to build.</p> <p>Prepare by searching for extra pictures of the engine you wish to model, either online or in your Rio Grande books.</p> <p>Boiler: Take care when you handle the boiler casting, as the handrail supports tend to break after bending 3 times.</p> <p>File and fit the fire box onto the rear of the Märklin frame, so it matches the dimensions provided in the instruction sheet, but do not affix it yet.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blog/K27_image1-1.jpg" alt="Wheels" title="Wheels"/></p> <p>Sketch of counterbalance attached to Märklin wheel[/caption]As stated in the instructions, getting the drivers operating is the heart of the kit assembly. I found just 9 eccentric wheel castings in my kit, one of which was not entirely circular. After carefully straightening each casting, file the sides and top of the outside counterweights. Next, using a fine metal thin sabre saw blade, clear the centric connection axle between the wheel cover and the counterweight. Try to get it centered or the suspension plate will wobble. Drill the hole in the wheel cover to fit over the side rod connecting hole on the Märklin driver wheels. Be careful not to damage the smaller holes in the counterweight. File flat the back of the wheel caps, leaving only the 2 opposed small rims to it between the red plastic wheel spokes. Start on one side by gluing each of the 4 wheel covers to the Märklin drivers using CA glue, starting at the far side. Using your finger nails press each wheel cover flat against the driver wheel before the glue sets. Inspect how good you succeeded in keeping the axles centered by turning the four axles while watching the axles behind the counterweights from the top. Continue to shave small amounts off the eccentric side of these axles. I used a small modeler’s saw blade that will fit between the wheels and needs no extra pressure except slightly flexing the blade from the end you’re holding. Keep turning the wheel while filing and check you create a round axle cross-section, not one with flat sides.</p> <p>Frame suspension: Following the instructions, file flat the inside of both frame suspension castings, but first check the drawings to prevent you end up with two right side frames. In fact these castings are asymmetric, with the end that has a hole in it going to the rear up against the fire box. Flatten the castings by lying it flat on a fine file doing the final sanding of the back. Using a low speed Dremel sanding disc, square the slots that go over the wheel axles. Fit on the Märklin frame and try to turn the wheels. Either remove more eccentricity from the connecting axles or slightly widen one side of a slot to allow free movement of all four drivers inside the suspension frame casting. As the sides will rest on the axles, leave some room around a wobbly axle or the frame will always move up and down In front, the suspension frame castings are supposed to fit between the cylinder casting. Remove some metal from the inside of the cylinder casting to allow the frame halves to freely sit over the driver wheels. In the rear, carefully file a small 1x1 mm notch to fit the frame sides under the fire box. Once the suspension frame plates fit over the drivers, glue the two Walschaert Y-shapes to the outside over the second driver with the forked side pointing to the front.</p> <p>Märklin frame and adapter trucks: The pilot and trailing trucks on my Märklin item #8896 Z scale engine are metal castings. Remove both trucks from the frame (remove the screws one at a time will keep the gear cover and drivers in place on the frame). Lift off the steel plate and snip off the point with 1 hole. On the casting, cut away the coupler pin and protrusion. File 1.5 mm off the top of the truck to come level with the top of the mounting eye and have the truck clear the firebox.</p> <p>Left over parts: I could not find where to use the 2 semicircular 3 mm wide steps/boxes.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blog/img_6528-6.jpg" alt="K-27 Assembled" title="K-27 Assembled"/></p> <p>Assembled locomotive, seen from the left[/caption] Tender: Add two 1 mm thick styrene shims between the tender trucks and the sub frame to clear the wheels and get the rear coupler at the correct height. Drill a hole to attach a connection bar between the tender and the engine. Also attach a small pin below the bottom of the firebox/engine cabin (eg. a thin tube pointing down, affixed with a small bolt from above).</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="trains-treinen"/><category term="rlw"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I had this RLW kit waiting for a couple of years. Finally, the time came to build it.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en-us"><title type="html">JMRI is more fluid</title><link href="https://ebroerse.nl/nl/blog/2016/jmri-is-more-fluid/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="JMRI is more fluid"/><published>2016-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2016/jmri-is-more-fluid</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2016/jmri-is-more-fluid/"><![CDATA[<p>As a Christmas holiday project, I contributed to the JMRI manual and translations. Fun, but it feels like lots of eyes are watching you (8,000 users worldwide!). JMRI is developed using <a href="https://java.net/">Java</a> and <a href="https://github.com/">GitHub</a> as its Version Control System (VCS). Genius!</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blog/GitDsktopPR-99x150.png" alt="GitDsktopPR"/></p> <p>See: <a href="https://jmri.org/">JMRI.org</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="trains-treinen"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a Christmas holiday project, I contributed to the JMRI manual and translations. Fun, but it feels like lots of eyes are watching you (8,000 users worldwide!). JMRI is developed using Java and GitHub as its Version Control System (VCS). Genius!]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en-us"><title type="html">Git it?</title><link href="https://ebroerse.nl/nl/blog/2015/git-it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Git it?"/><published>2015-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2015/git-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ebroerse.nl/blog/2015/git-it/"><![CDATA[<p>To assist in the development of the <a href="http://jmri.org">JMRI</a> Java application for running trains, I signed on to <a href="http://www.github.com">GitHub</a> and installed GitHub Desktop. I figured out how to clone the original JMRI repository to my own GitHub remote repo. Creating a Branch to write new or improved code for web pages and configuration files on GitHub web was next.</p> <p>Then came the step to clone my remote repo to a local copy on my computer. <a href="https://desktop.github.com">GitHub Desktop</a> looked like a perfect program to do this. So now I had a large folder on my desktop with a copy of my repo, letting me edit any file directly from the Finder in either Espresso or an image editing app. You need this local repo 1 to delete and add files anyway.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blog/IMG_5475.png" alt="GitHub diagram" title="my Git Setup"/></p> <div class="caption"> Diagram of remote and local files </div> <p>But when I added the Netbeans IDE there was a mix-up in the source and target files. You save on disk space by pointing NetBeans to local GitHub repo 1 as its Git master. But a Commit + Push in NetBeans shows up like the exact opposite in GitHub Desktop: when I added a word in NB, GitHub Desktop showed that Commit as deleting that word from the files it was comparing. That setup with one index won’t work!</p> <p>So I suggest you let both Git clients clone the same remote repo. And only edit in repo 2 inside NetBeans, not at a file level. Added benefit: this looks exactly the same when you work on 2 computers, with your remote GitHub repo as the one and only central place from which to make Pull Requests.</p> <h2 id="oops-a-conflict"><em>Oops</em>, a conflict?!</h2> <p>Whatever your workflow looks like, when you make a commit or update a branch from the current upstream master, GitHub may signal a <em>conflict</em> which you have to solve. GitHub Web marks “a conflict” but doesn’t tell you what or why. Open GitHub Desktop to solve a conflict: scroll through the list to find the problematic file. To the right look for the »»»&gt; mark(s). Right click and select “Show in Finder” and open the file with your favorite editor. Choose which part to retain and what to delete. Delete the »&gt; lines, Save and return to GitHub Desktop. Choose Commit to [your branch], and Sync with your remote repo. You’re ready to merge the Pull Request.</p> <p>Happy Gitting!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="computers"/><category term="trains-treinen"/><category term="java"/><category term="jmri"/><category term="osx"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[To assist in the development of the JMRI Java application for running trains, I signed on to GitHub and installed GitHub Desktop. I figured out how to clone the original JMRI repository to my own GitHub remote repo. Creating a Branch to write new or improved code for web pages and configuration files on GitHub web was next.]]></summary></entry></feed>